#### Kontakt

dominik.lenda@protonmail.co

www.linkedin.com/in/dominik-lenda-a0097b200 (LinkedIn) linktr.ee/dominik.lenda (Personal) github.com/dominik-lenda (Personal) www.credly.com/users/dominik-lenda (Portfolio)

## Główne umiejętności

Python Microsoft Azure SQL

## Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

#### Honors-Awards

Scholarship of Minister of Science and Higher Education in Poland Laureate of the Diamond Grant

award

Laureate of the "The Best of The Best! 3.0" scholarship

Arctic Code Vault Contributor

Rector's scholarships for best academic achievement

#### **Publications**

The Relationship Between Adaptive Strategy Selection And Cognitive Effort: An Eye-Tracking Study

# **Dominik Lenda**

Aspiring Cloud Data Engineer | Psychological Scientist & Data Analyst | Azure certified

Wrocław

## Podsumowanie

Hi, I'm Dominik.

I'm changing my profession from psychological researcher to cloud data engineer. Every day I document my cloud learnings on Twitter.

Psychological science is full of fascinating questions and research problems. I've had an exciting opportunity to explore and apply tools, theories of decision making. However, I realized the most interesting to me in my scientific journey was problem-solving of technical nature, especially programming.

That's why I'm getting into IT; I need more problem-solving. I have experience in a few tech-related fields, for example, data analysis and web development. I had a gist of many software development areas, and familiarity with multiple programming languages such as Python, R. However, the most unknown and exotic to me was cloud computing. Out of pure curiosity, I've started exploring the Cloud, and after a few months, all I can say is, I love it. Building on my experience in data analysis, I pursue a Data Engineer path in the cloud.

Currently, I participate in the #100DaysOfCloud, the challenge of learning cloud computing 100 days in a row. Each day I document my learnings on Twitter. Also, I have Azure Fundamentals certification by passing the AZ-900 exam. I'm preparing for other certifications such as Azure DP-203. My main goal is to build things in the cloud and solve real-world problems; certifications are only the help to navigate it.

# Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

My current interests:

- # Microsoft Azure
- # Cloud Computing

- # SQL, T-SQL
- •# MySQL, SQL Server
- # Python
- •# Linux
- # Git

## Doświadczenie

Uniwersytet SWPS
Principal Investigator
wrzesień 2018 - Present (3 lata)
Wrocław, Woj. Dolnoślaskie, Polska

I conducted a €40,000 research grant project on cognitive underpinnings of experience-based choices.

### Main responsibilities:

- building statistical models,
- manipulating data in R,
- preparing computer-based experiments in Python,
- writing proposals, publications.

## Pogotowie Statystyczne Data Analyst marzec 2020 - Present (1 rok 6 mies.)

I am a data analyst and R programmer.

#### Main responsibilities:

- contacting clients,
- programming in R,
- preparing statistical models,
- applying statistical inference in Bayesian and frequentist methodology,
- writing reports of data analysis for scientific publications.

## Curate Science Web Developer grudzień 2019 - styczeń 2021 (1 rok 2 mies.)

I worked as a web developer on a web application that organizes scientific articles. The final goal of this enterprise was to promote open science practices.

My main responsibilities:

- using Git,
- web application development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React;
- web scrapping metadata of scientific journals using Python, BeautifulSoup, and Scrapy;
- interacting with Google Cloud Platform.

# Wykształcenie

Uniwersytet SWPS

Master of Arts, Psychology · (2014 - 2019)